When working with larger documents, you
may wish to insert page numbers, the
date, a company logo, or other information
into a section of the letter or document.
If you want it to appear on all
pages, you would primarily use the
headers and footers tool for this.
To access the headers and footers
tool, if you go to the insert
tab, move your mouse along.
You will see the header drop down.
Now there are range of preformatted
templates for the headers or footers.
But if you just wish to edit a blank
header or footer, you would just simply go
down to the bottom and click edit header.
In this example, I'm just going to
insert a date, and as you can see,
now that I'm in the header and footer,
it's indicated that there's a dotted
line, it's in the heading section.
If I move down the page, you can see,
it's indicated that the footer is there.
And again, it's indicated that
this section here and this section
here will be the header and footer.
So I'm simply going to insert the date.
I'll select the day/time, the option I'm
going to select is that one and click OK.
So that has inserted the
date into the header.
Now, as you can see, it is nice and
clear there, but if I click away
from that, it goes slightly grey.
Now that means I can't edit it.
To actually get into the header
and footer again, there's a quicker
way than going to the insert.
If I just double click alongside
it, it will automatically open
up the header or the footer.
I now also wish to add a page
numbers to the document's footer.
So if I go down to the footer.
Again it's a blank footer, or I
can just click edit footer, there
are templates there available.
Different ways it could be formatted.
You're simply going to go to edit footer
and in there, I'm going to select page
number and it's going to be a plain
number and that has entered that there.
So if I double click away from that, I
can now see that the page number's in the
bottom and the date as is in the header.
If I was typing in this document
and I went on to page two.
So if I just press the enter key,
to take me down to a new page,
as you can see, every page, it is
adding the date and new page number.